Finding Aid for the Allan H. Kurtzman Collection of Material about Beat Writers and Artists LSC.0362
UCLA Library Special Collections
Allan H. Kurtzman collection of material about Beat Writers and Artists
circa 1950-1989
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kurtzman, Allan H.
LSC.0362
1 unknown (3 oversize boxes)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332723606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of printed material about William S. Burroughs, Allen Ginsberg, and Michael McClure.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Related Material
Collection of Bookseller's Catalogs of Beat Literature (Collection 1648). Available at the Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Hirado Porcelain of Japan: from the Kurtzman Family Collection / [organized by] Robert T. Singer and Hollis Goodall. Available at the UCLA Arts Library. Call number: NK 4399 H57 L67 1997.
Beat generation.; McClure, Michael; Burroughs, William S.; Ginsberg, Allen
- Biographical
  - Amram, David and Rambling Jack Elliott
    - No Title. Sound recording: 45 rpm. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Beat Poets, etc.
    - History. Manuscript material, author unknown., n.d.; Typescript (photocopy). (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Scope and Contents note
      Chapter 1 is entitled The pre-war origins of the post-war avant-garde. With Appendix, a bibliography in different paper.
  - Berrigan, Ted
    - C Press [Journal] Publication material. Announcement., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Bockris, Victor(?) Edward (?)
    - Poetry Anthology Manuscript. Manuscript material., n.d.; In notebook with label. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Six poems [asked of various poets, e.g. Aram Saroyan, Gerard Malanga, ...], an assembly of statements by the poets and photo and other copies of the poems selected.
      Appears not to have been published.
      General note
      (not in ORION or MELVYL under this title)
  - Burroughs
    - Printed Material About [Various items not listed by folder]. (Box 1)
    - Burroughs, William. Letters to Various Persons., 1960s. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Notes and enclosures. Primarily to a seeming collector, Jake Swartz.
      Includes mockup of British edition Naked Lunch cover, etc.
  - Corso, Gregory
    - Letters to Various Persons., 1958, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Christmas greetings, etc. Includes postcard to Robert La Vigne.
  - Thirteen
    - Publication material. Thirteen, with header Over Matter., n.d.; Galley proofs. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Unable to determine publication.
  - For the Paris Biennale and Unlabeled
    - Sound recordings., June 11, 1965 and n.d.; Reel to reel (2). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Poem Beginning: Brief the Moments of Ecstasy
    - Manuscript material., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Collage, painting, etc. Cut up poem on reverse, beginning: Stop the changes get a new number ....
  - Letters to Various Persons
    - Dear Jackie mio, etc.., n.d.; Typescript. (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Seemingly kept as a journal, as well.
  - Eigner, Larry
    - Penny Poems. Publications., 1960.; Two newsprint broadsides. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence. Publications., 1960s.; Copies. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Reviews etc.
  - Letters
    - Postcards, etc., 1969, 1980, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Includes note on City Lights postcard, poster for reading.
  - Ginsberg, Allen
    - Printed material about. (Box 2)
      [Various items not listed by folder]
  - Letters to Various Persons
    - Notes, etc., 1965-1970. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Primarily to Herbert Huncke, also Robert La Vigne, etc.
      Most are notes, evidently about giving Huncke money (for habit). Some on City Lights notepads.
  - Various Poems
    - Manuscript material., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Beginning: A shadow of the angel. Entitled: Man is naked without secrets armed men lack this joy [signed Allen Ginsberg]
  - Allen Ginsberg Live!
    - Sound recording., Cassette. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Allen Ginsberg with the Gluons
    - Sound recording. Sue your Parents. Birdbrain records. 45 rpm. Signed to Herbert Huncke., 1983. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ginsberg, Allen and Anne Waldman
    - Beauty and the Beast. Sound recording., August 1975.; Cassette (2 copies). (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, Burroughs, and Various Other Beat Figures
    - Sound Recordings (Long Playing Records). Various titles, including Howl, Ferlinghetti's Impeach Eisenhower, Burroughs Reading Ali's Smile, etc., Long playing records, most in sleeves with photographs. (Box 6)
  - Kurtzman, Allan
    - Mailings received. Various., 1960s-1980s.; Mimeograph sheets. (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Letters for Timothy Leary defense fund, publication announcements, etc. No actual correspondence except to enclose book lists, catalogs, etc.
  - La Vigne, Robert
    - Gallery Materials. Ephemera. (?)., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      The Lion (Polk Street, San Francisco gallery), Notes about Ginsberg, etc.
  - Lawrence, D.H.
    - Lady Chatterley's Lover. Grove Press court documents. Victor Weybright., 1959. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - McClure, Michael
    - Printed material about. (Box 3)
  - The Blossom; or, Billy the Kid
    - Manuscript material. (?). Billy the Kid in envelope to Roi Jones., 1960; Copy(?). (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Josephine
    - Manuscript material(?)., n.d.; Mimeograph(?). (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Feast
    - Manuscript material., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Also Ghost tantra 51, Fuck ode. Notes on first page signed Rick. Letter with Fuck ode to Terry. Poems signed by McCLure.
  - McClure, Michael and Others
    - Pale Pearl Pink on the Walls., n.d.; Typescript (photocopy or mimeograph), beginning p.21. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Manuscript(?) material. Also material by Stuart Perkoff, etc.
  - Ossman, Dave With Michael McClure
    - The Sullen Art. Sound recording., November 1964.; Reel-to-reel. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Di Prima, Diane
    - Poet's Vaudeville. Publication. n.p.., n.d.; Mimeograph(?). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - For Z
    - Manuscript material., April 1959.; 1 leaf. Typescript with holograph corrections and notes. Signed by the poet. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Poem, beginning: I shall grow mint and teach the child her colors.